ABOUT ME

I'm an experienced Android Developer skilled in Java, Kotlin, Retrofit, Jetpack and all other flashy new (and old) things. I love programming and I'm glad i was fortunate enough to combine my hobby and a job into one. Apart from programming i love spending time with my fiancee and our 3 cats, making model WW2 airplanes and going out into the nature away

from civilization:)

SKILLS	
ANDROID	
KOTLIN	
JAVA	
DI (KOIN, Dagger 2, KODEIN)	
COROUTINES	
SQL	
NoSQL	
GIT	
.NET	
PYTHON	

LINKS

GitHub

LinkedIn

Andrej Zentner

SENIOR ANDROID DEVELOPER

Medulinska 2, 31000 Osijek, Croatia

+ 385 91 1221 116

andrej.zentner@mscommunity.net

Senior Android Developer / Team Lead

Android in my spare time

PlayStore apps

colaborated with

LiveData, Coroutines

Again a slight career shift - was learning

Worked on a plethora of applications for

clients around the world - both B2B and

Had roles both as Team Lead and a Senior

100% Remote (and not looking to change

Preferred (and most used) Android stack:

Kotlin, RoomDB, Retrofit, MVVM, Koin,

Android Dev within companies I've

WORK EXPERIENCE

CYPHER

Dec 2014 – present

Clients/employers: app: country: emp. duration

Teltech – part of IAC (Tinder, Match.com) family: RoboKiller: USA: 1.6 years

Kamino: Global.ID: EU: 6 months Impaddo: B2B application:EU: 1.9 vears

Wolkswagen Subsidiary: Local events/discounts app: EU: 1 year + far to many to list here

SIEMENS

Apr 2014 - Jan 2016

Senior Java Developer

- Career shift was learning Java in my spare
- Designed, implemented and maintained features for a robust monitoring and charging system, in use by large telecoms (T-Mobile, Verizon, etc..)
- Used Scrum methodology
- Technologies used: Java, SQL, Python

STARNET

May 2013 - May 2014

.NET Developer

- Worked on various desktop applications (various CMS solutions)
- Designed, implemented and maintained features across multiple different applications
- Technologies used: .NET (C# and VB), MSSQL, JavaScript, DevExpress

MICROSOFT

Jul 2011 - Jun 2012

.NET Intern

- Worked on internal applications
- Technologies used: .NET, MSSQL, Windows Phone SDK, JavaScript

Education

FACULTY OF ORGANISATION AND INFORMATICS

2009. - 2014.

CIVIL ENGINEERING

2001. – 2015.

Bachelor of Computer Science

Information Technology

High School Diploma

Note:

I'm only open for fully remote positions.

You can find my code samples on GitHub. Newest repo is always the closest to the way I'm writting code at the moment.

I'm happy to do take home assignments related to Android – always love to explore some new tech/lib while doing these.

If your interview process includes solving University level algorithmic questions, please reject my application.

PUBLICATIONS

Apr 2018



Multithreading in .NET and Java: A Reality Check

Source

NOTABLE PROJECTS

RoboKiller



Android Call Blocking application. 500k monthly, 40k daily active users. Implementing new features, bug fixing and maintenance. Technologies used: Kotlin, Retrofit, Jetpack, MVVM

Global ID



Android application that aims to unify various identity verification methods into one. Ambitious project. Technologies used: Kotlin, Retrofit, Jetpack, RxJava, Dagger 2, MVP

Real Estate App



A CMS for real estate agents. Worked as a Team Lead. Technologies used: Java, Retrofit, RxJava, Dagger, Realm

Bus Tracking App



An app for bus drivers and passengers, it's use case is to track the bus's position and show the users the arrival time, bus stops, and additional info. Worked as a Team Lead. Technologies used: Java, Koin, Retrofit, Maps API, Coroutines, LiveData, MVVM

Instant Messaging App



Simple instant messaging app. Worked as a Team Lead. Technologies used: Kotlin, Koin, Jetpack, Retrofit, Coroutines, MVVM

Also worked on the backend side. Technologies used: Java , MySQL